So now we are going to add the zombie spawner. As you know that we already have the script
so you can go ahead and open this up. Right here we are going to remove the start and
update method and then to top we are going to add these variables. So the first is a header
and in this we make a reference to all of the zombie prefabs then to the spawn points
where the zombie will be spawned and then this is a reference to how many zombies will
be spawned and then this is for spawning only once. Like for example in some places if
you want to spawn zombies twice then you can do that and where you just only have to
spawn zombies once you insert this to two and then this is the spawn which will keep
drive if they are spawned or not. Okay so right down below make a method by the name
of spawn zombies in which first of all right here we check that if prefabs and point
exist okay and if it doesn't exist okay so if it is equal to 0 then we show this that
spawner missing prefabs or spawn points and then we will run but if it exist then right
here we spawn zombies based on come set in the inspector okay for example by default it
is 5 it can be 2 or 3 or how many zombies you want to spawn then right here we randomly pick
a zombie type and then right here we pick a random spawn point and then we create or you
can see instantiate the zombie in the scene at the spawn point position and rotation all
right now when we want to spawn zombies we want when the player hit a collider somewhere
then in front of the player we will spawn that zombies okay so for that right here at
the top make a one trigger enter method in which we first of all check if whatever enter
is not player we return and also if it is spawn once then we also want to return and then
after that we just simply spawn the zombies and then we mark spawning as done so it doesn't
happen again all right this is all for the zombie spawner now let me show you how you can
start this up in the game right here as you know that we have this objective also when
the player picks the come from there and the player if the player walks in the forward direction
then we want to now spawn these zombies okay so we will spawn zombies right here at
different okay so let me actually make a 3d cube here it is okay let's move it right
here and then begin resize this like this and then we are there and there okay to say
but let's smash render actually enable it move down okay we need to move this up actually
like this that's it okay let's move it up that's okay now let's just say with that make
the trigger as is triggered and also change it's clear to trigger okay and you can do the
same for the other triggers as well change it's clear to trigger so this cube one will
be our zombie failure one all right to this dragon drop the zombie spawner script down
the zombie spawner script we need to wear the zombies so click on GameObject zombies pre-fabs
here they are let's lock that and select all of the zombies try and drop it in there now
unlock it okay so let's zombie trigger one there it is we need to now add the spawn points
so the spawn points should be in here okay so first spawn point will be right here so I'm
gonna add a 3D cube this will be our first spawn point so name it as one and duplicate
it this will be our second okay in the first zombie we're gonna add just two zombies
okay right here that's it now name this as two and make sure to track both of these inside
the zombie trigger and then try and drop this zombie trigger one inside objective point
okay and select zombie trigger one try and drop the first spawn point then the second and
the number of zombies to spawn will be two and this will be just happen once all right
now select these two and disable the mesh actually you can remove the box color and the
mesh on these spawn points all right now let's play the game as you know that in the
previous video our first objective was already completed so if you play the game again as
you can see it has already completed so I press the paper done it will research the progress
now as you can see it shows find something for production and as you can see the objective
one is active so I'm just gonna restart the game again right because right now we
doesn't have any menu but by which we reset the progress and restart the game so I'm
just gonna do it when we okay now first objective is find something for protection right
so now as soon as we get trigger inside the zombie trigger now as you can see in the
arcade two zombies are added to the him as you can see right there okay whoops that was
just a punch we will be leading this point sound don't worry now if we pick the pistol
and let's move outside over there is the first zombie running two wizards kill the zombie
all right fine UNP the next zombies right here walking there it is okay the second zombie
all right so the objective and everything is working perfectly fine okay
now in this way you can add different type of zombies for each of the objective
okay I'm gonna go ahead and do it for the second and third objective as well so our second
objective is right here so we're gonna add zombies then right there okay so what I'm
gonna do now is try to zombies two triggers so I'm thrilled he made a cube okay here it
is made 2020 actually seven or nine would be good then 20 actually let's make it 50 since
this is a trigger so change it to trigger and then this will be triggered as well all right
so now disable that and what we need to be zombie trigger so this will be zombie trigger
two and this air the zombie spawner now for zombies you're gonna grab and drop these zombies
in there for these point points we will create points now so the points will be right
here okay so first only will be spawn right here at a cube there it is this will be your
first point let's duplicate it since now we have UNP we can add more zombies so second
where spawn point third four fifth six and then seven right here okay one ten two three
oh five six and seven all right these are the spawn points right over inside the zombie
trigger to lock it select all of these spawn points right drop it in there number of zombies
spawn will be seven or let's just make it nine all right and you can add the zombie trigger
to inside the objective two okay now and for the third one we will not be spawning in
a zombie since it is right there closer but for the first one we can add more zombies I
think two are really low number so I'm just gonna go ahead and add one zombie
right here okay so let's add a 3 cube in here and then one right there then one right
there in one there okay so one two then this will be three then four five and six okay
from all of them disable the mesh render actually you can remove these things from there
try and drop it in zombie trigger one select zombie trigger one in here lock it and try
and drop the other spawn points increase the number of zombies to seven okay that is it
check the objective two spawn points it has the box color and everything so I'm just
gonna remove it from there as well that is it okay if we play the game since our first
objective was completed when the game start as you can see our first objective is completed
now the second one is available but let's reset it okay and let's restart the game and
see if the zombie appears now or not all right let's walk okay the zombie appears right
there as you saw in the distance let's pick the pistol and let's try shooting them all
now it looks good let's reload and let's move forward and check that other area as well
okay there's the second zombie all it looks really scary to be honest
okay there's some piece right there okay so
if you notice all of these zombies are spawning perfectly fine okay now more zombies
are spawned in front of us but now the second objective is to find you MP
quite this building doesn't have colored us so we need to add colored us here okay here is the second
now we have two rifles the first one in the pistol then we have the UMP
key there are these zombies are here where did I kill all of them?
all right so now as you can see it looks really good now okay all of these zombies are
still inside the game as you can see their bodies doesn't get removed so don't worry we will
be adding something for that okay but as you can see now our second objective wasn't done
because I told you there were no clearly in the household you were unable to touch that
colored okay now we have a third objective right here which will not be completed because the second one was not
all right so let's go ahead and fix that it's this building right here if you select it
okay it's this whole building I think the floor left the floor don't have any
let's add color on this rock so I'm gonna add a mesh color over there and mesh
color is already added here let's select these okay mesh color is added and also make sure
that you move them to default as well so that it plays the footsteps sound right here as
well default then here as well if we select the inside floor okay box color was added let's
set it to default set this one to default as well in it mesh color than this floor and right
here we have this punch to which a box color is added that's why our objective wasn't
completed so I'm gonna remove that and add a mesh color to it okay change that to default
change this to default as well that's it and let me also select this second objective is this
one we're hearing increase it's color word now this will work perfectly fine